mmh.com 2019-12-05

# Privacy Policy

Effective March 13, 2019

This privacy policy describes how your personal information is collected, stored, used, and shared when you interact with the products, services, and programs offered from Peerless Media LLC’s network of publications and web sites (this “Site” including peerlessmedia.com, peerlessresearch.com, logisticsmgmt.com, mmh.com, scmr.com, supplychain247.com, materialhandling247, digitalengineering247.com, nextgensupplychainconference.com).

Our location and contact information:  
Peerless Media LLC  
℅ Privacy Manager  
111 Speen Street, Suite 200  
Framingham MA 01701 USA  
E-mail: [privacymanager@peerlessmedia.com](mailto:privacymanager@peerlessmedia.com)

**THE INFORMATION WE COLLECT**  
We collect information you provide to us, including personally identifiable information, in the course of using, engaging with, or otherwise interacting with our products, services, and programs. Through this interaction you can, among other activities, subscribe to one of our products (such as newsletters or magazines); request information from us or one of our trusted partners; engage in various activities like entering contests or sweepstakes, registering for webinars or in-person events, responding to surveys, voting in polls or otherwise expressing an opinion; or participate in one of our online forums or communities.

We may also collect information about your personal or professional interests, opinions and/or your use of various products, services and programs. For example, we may ask you to provide your job responsibilities or the industry in which you work to qualify for a free magazine subscription.

In some cases you can submit information about other people. For example, you might submit a person’s name, company information, and mailing or email address to nominate the person for an industry award.

In addition to the information you provide to us directly, we, our partners, advertising networks, advertisers or other third party service providers may also collect non-personally identifiable information when you visit our web pages, open our emails, or engage with any of our other products or services. This includes such information as type of browser and operating system you are using, your IP address, your device identifiers, your internet service provider, location-based information, and the content you interacted with, viewed, or accessed. This data may be combined and linked with data from other sources.

For example, we use Google Analytics to help us understand how our customers use the Site. Visitors can opt-out of Google Analytics for display advertising and customize Google display network ads using the Ads Settings. Visitors may also opt-out of additional data collection via the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on. Third-party vendors show our ads on sites across the Internet. We and third-party vendors, including Google, use first-party cookies and third-party cookies to inform, optimize, and serve ads based on someone’s past visits to our websites.

**HOW WE USE COLLECTED INFORMATION**  
We use the personal information that you provide to us to provide products, services and programs to you. As part of a subscription and/or registration agreement, subscribers and registrants will be contacted by us through mail, e-mail, and/or phone to communicate with them about their subscription and/or registration. They will be contacted for renewal, re-qualification, surveys, updates concerning their account profile and special offers related to their subscription and/or registration. You may unsubscribe from newsletters and other email communications at any time by clicking the unsubscribe link at the bottom of the email you are no longer interested in.

From time to time we may contact you (or permit selected third parties to contact you) to notify you of special offers or other products, services, programs, or events. By providing your email address and/or phone number you consent to us contacting you by email or telephone.

The information we collect is also used to improve the content of our web pages, to customize the content and layout of our pages, and/or to notify visitors about updates to our website.

We may offer contests, sweepstakes, promotions, editorial features or other offerings that are sponsored or co-sponsored by or presented with identified third parties. By participating in such activities or offerings, your IP address and the personally identifiable information you voluntarily submit may be provided to third parties we trust. Peerless Media LLC does not control the third parties’ use of this information. Generally, we will let you know at the time of collection if a product is sponsored. If you wish to change your contact preferences with an individual exhibitor/sponsor, please follow their own unsubscribe request details. Unsubscribing with Peerless Media LLC stops Peerless from sharing your information with third parties and from contacting you about issues not related to your subscriptions, but it does not affect any third-parties with whom we have shared your information from contacting you. In order to unsubscribe from communications from third parties, you must do that directly with the third-party company.

Certain information — such as your password and credit card number — is never disclosed in any form whatsoever to any outside party.

**SHARING YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION**  
We may disclose your personal information to selected third parties outside Peerless Media LLC for purposes associated with payment processing, the supply of products or services, for website administration or elsewhere when you have consented to such disclosures. These third parties are contractually bound to use personal information only to perform the services that we hire them to provide.

In addition, we make available sponsored content, and content provided to us from third parties. In return for access to this content, your personal information may be shared with those third parties, and the information will be governed by those parties’ privacy policies as well as ours. Peerless Media LLC does not bear any responsibility for any actions or policies of such third parties. If you do not wish to have your information shared with a third party, please do not access sponsored or third party content on our site.

We may also disclose personal information to comply with applicable laws and regulations, to respond to a subpoena, search warrant or other lawful request for information we receive, or to otherwise protect our rights.

Finally, we may also share your personal information to any successor pursuant to an asset sale, merger, consolidation, restructuring, reorganization, liquidation or other similar transaction involving Peerless Media LLC or this Site.

**ACCESSING/CORRECTING/UPDATING PERSONAL INFORMATION**  
You may view and update information that you previously submitted to Peerless Media LLC by sending us an e-mail through the e-mail link provided above or writing to us at the above address. Current subscribers and registrants can also access and change their information by selecting the appropriate link in the email product, or on the website where their current subscription/registration resides. A request to change information may not be accommodated if the request conflicts with legal requirements or could result in incorrect information. Requests to view or change personal information may take a few days to process.

**COOKIES**  
We use cookies to store website visitors’ preferences, record session information (such as items that visitors add to their shopping carts), record user-specific information such as what pages users access or visit, customize advertising content and/or frequency, customize web page content based on a visitor’s browser type or other information that the visitor sends, and store users’ names and passwords. A cookie is a small amount of data sent to your browser from a server and stored on your computer’s hard drive. Most browsers allow users to block the receipt of cookies, but doing so may compromise your ability to use certain features of our websites. We do not collect Personally Identifiable Information in this way, but if you provide us with Personally Identifiable Information, we may associate that information with the information that is collected automatically.

We also use third-party advertising companies to serve ads to visitors on our websites. These companies may use information (not including visitors’ names, addresses, email addresses, or telephone numbers) about visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to visitors. To learn more about behavioral advertising practices or to opt-out of this type of advertising for some companies, you can visit [http://www.networkadvertising.org](https://www.mmh.com/?URL=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.networkadvertising.org) and http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp

**AD SERVERS AND THIRD PARTIES**  
We may use third parties to present or serve advertisements, including advertisements based on online behavior to conduct research or collect additional personally identifiable information. Additionally, third parties may place and use tracking mechanisms (e.g., tracking pixels) on our web pages or in the emails we send to you. This Privacy Policy does not cover any use of information that such third parties may have collected from you (e.g., type of browser, operating system, domain name, day and time of visit, page(s) visited) or the methods used by the third-parties to collect that information (e.g. cookies, web beacons and clear gifs).

Some of our web pages, products, and services contain links to third party sites and services whose privacy practices may be different than ours. We also allow you to connect with other third party sites and services. You should consult the other third party sites’ and services’ privacy notices in order to better understand their privacy practices.

**SECURITY**  
Peerless Media LLC takes every precaution to protect your information from unauthorized use. When you submit sensitive information via our websites, the information is protected both online and offline.

Children should always get permission from their parents before sending any information about themselves (such as their names, e-mail addresses, and phone numbers) over the Internet, to us or to anyone else. We won’t knowingly allow anyone under 13 to register with us or to provide any other personal information. If you’re under 13, please do not provide us with any personal information about yourself (such as your name, your e-mail address or your phone number).

**USERS OUTSIDE THE U.S.**  
Our websites are operated in the United States. If you are located in the European Union or elsewhere outside of the United States, be aware that any information you provide to us will be transferred to the United States. By using our websites, participating in any of our products or services and/or providing us with your information, you consent to this transfer and to our collection and use of your information as set forth above.

**GENERAL DATA PROTECTION REGULATION (GDPR)**  
With the implementation of GDPR in May 2018 we are updating our privacy policy and becoming more transparent with how we collect and use data about our customers who reside in the European Union.

The following additional data collection and handling rules will be applied to customers located in the following countries of the European Union (EU): Austria, Belgium, Bulgaria, Croatia, Cyprus, Czech Republic, Denmark, Estonia, Finland, France, Germany, Greece, Hungary, Ireland, Italy, Latvia, Lithuania, Luxembourg, Malta, The Netherlands, Poland, Portugal, Romania, Slovakia, Slovenia, Spain, Sweden, United Kingdom:

* Emails. No marketing messages will be sent to any customer in the EU without explicit permissions. Any person receiving an email can change permissions at any time by emailing [privacymanager@peerlessmedia.com](mailto:privacymanager@peerlessmedia.com).

* Data. No personally identifiable information will be shared with third party organizations without the customer’s explicit permission. Customers may ask for a data audit and request that we remove all data from our database by contacting our our Privacy Manager at [privacymanager@peerlessmedia.com](mailto:privacymanager@peerlessmedia.com). 

**POLICY UPDATES**  
From time to time, we may use provided information for new, unanticipated uses not previously disclosed in our privacy policy. If our information practices change we will immediately post any adjustments to our policy on this website. This will serve as your notification of these changes. If you are concerned about how your information is used, bookmark this page and check back periodically.

**ENFORCEMENT**  
If you feel that this site is not following its stated information policy, please contact us through the above postal address or e-mail link.
